motor vehicle insurance so what is the
need for motor insurance in the event of
an accident there can be significant
financial loss to a vehicle owner
besides injury in such cases the only
remedy to reduce the financial loss is
motor insurance motor insurance protects
an individual against financial losses
arising out of accidental damages theft
of vehicle financial compensation for
death of a third party due to an
accident
do you know motor insurance is one of
the mandatory documents to have while
driving a vehicle on Indian roads one
must have a motor insurance to cover
third party risk which is mandatory by
law so what is motor insurance motor
insurance is a protection to the
policyholder against financial losses
incurred as a result of accidental
damages and against liabilities arising
due to use of vehicle motor insurance is
also a contract whereby an insurance
company agrees to indemnify the insured
for losses incurred as a result of
accidental damages and against
liabilities arising due to use a vehicle
subject to policy terms and conditions
now let's look at the history of the
motor insurance industry the motor
insurance industry has evolved over the
years in multiple ways this included
detailing of the industry on pricing
terms in the year 2007 and once again in
2008 motor insurance worldwide remains
the largest contributor to general
insurance the motor insurance segment
contributes the maximum to the general
insurance industry numbers against
damage caused by natural and man-made
calamities including acts of terrorism
vehicle owners can avail of own damaged
personal accident and liability coverage
all in one policy